Paterne MALLE

Web developer

paternmalle@gmail.com

07 832 959 448

Leeds, UK

French web-developer, graduated recently, following an intensive one year course, including a three month internship. Looking to put my technical skills and life experience to work in a team environment interested in someone with a non standard professional path.

Main tech skills	Soft skills
Html, CSS, Javascript, React JS, Git, API.	Teamwork, Adaptability, Autonomy, Critical thinking, Quantitative skills, Analysis, Synthesis.
Other tech skills	Languages
PHP, Laravel, WordPress, Node, PWA, Bootstrap.	English: proficient.French: native.

Education

Web developer: 2019 - 2020 Simplon school, Level 5 equivalent

- Content of the course: Html, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Git, Node, PHP, Laravel, SQL, WordPress.
- · Basics of SEO and web design.
- · Introduction to agile methodologies.
- Opquast certification: good practises for web (UX, accessibility, security, e-commerce).
- · Majority of practical exercises.
- · Many small projects in teams of three to four people.
- Presentations in front of public varying from the class to 50 people.

BPREA Poultry farming: 2011 A level equivalent

- · Two, one month practical internships.
- Technical and economic course for enterprise management.

CAP Carpentry: 2008 NVQ level 2 equivalent

- Two, one month practical internships.
- Workflow conception, process organization.
- · Attention to detail, problem solving.

Master's degree in sociology: 2001 - 2006 University of Caen.

- · Self-discipline.
- · Critical thinking, documenting.
- · Survey design, data gathering and analysis.

Work experience

Practical Internship (3 months): 2020 Com3elles.

Small communication company, specialized in design, advice, and website conception using the CMS Joomla! and WordPress.

- Improvement of a Joomla! component (changing a data typology into an other one).
- Responsible for improving a plugin for Joomla!, using Googlemap, Openstreetmap, Leaflet and Algolia.

Cheese maker: 2017 - 2018 Artisanal cheese factory

- Elected staff representative for 30 employees.
- · Teamwork, reactivity and improvisation.
- · Reorganization of certain manufacturing processes.

Farmer and woodworker: 2008 - 2017 Collaborative homestead

- Creation and management of an organic free range egg workshop of 450 hens.
- Construction of a 400m² new sheepfold.
- Living, working and deciding as a team fluctuating between 5 and 12 members.
- Teamwork, autonomy, adaptation, improvisation, constancy.
- Client relation/sales with professionals and customers.

Personal projects

Link to my Github: https://github.com/Patern14

Pokedex

- · Made with React JS and react-router-dom.
- · Retrieve data from pokeAPI.
- Display the first 20 pokemons, load the following 20, display a random pokemon.
- Show details of the selected pokemon including their types and evolutions.

Flexbox reminder

- · DOM manipulation with Javascript.
- An interactive reminder for Flexbox properties where you can see the result of the different options for the Container and the Content.

Sm4rty

- A reproduction of the Smarty website homepage.
- · Media queries for desktop and mobile versions.

Connect4

- · A Javascript version of the four in a row game.
- · Victory conditions, reset button.

Interests

Sciences, technologies, UI/UX, Boardgames, Woodworking, Ecology, Sports, Japan, USA, History.